<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<execution_prompt version="1.0" task="P5-Task-7" milestone="EA-5" authored="2026-04-21" sdo_firing="post-EA-4-merge" staging="awaiting-colead-completion-review">

  <comprehension_gate>
    <instruction>
      MANDATORY FIRST ACTION: Before any branch creation, file edits, or commands, read this entire prompt and all required attachments in full.
      Then present a structured comprehension summary to the Lead Architect (or the Co-Lead reviewer under the DEC-12 peer-review lattice) covering:
        (a) milestone objective in your own words
        (b) work items with 1 sentence each
        (c) files to READ and files to WRITE
        (d) exact structural requirements for docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md and docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md
        (e) ORACLE strategy for this DOCS-ONLY synthesis milestone
        (f) risks or ambiguities (specifically: synthesis-only milestone with zero production or test file reads; only the audit artifact itself and the two skipped-test sites are in scope)
        (g) EXACT deliverable structure, recited VERBATIM from this prompt:
            - branch to create: feature/p5-task7-ea5-synthesis from main at a3419e9
            - files to WRITE: docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md and docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md only
            - docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md must retain exactly these 6 top-level sections in this order:
              1. ## Coverage Map
              2. ## Stale Test Inventory
              3. ## Assertion Quality Findings
              4. ## Boundary Violations
              5. ## Prioritized Gap Report
              6. ## Pre-existing Skip Analysis
            - preserve sections 1-4 and the EA Index rows EXACTLY as they appear on main — EA-5 adds ZERO content to sections 1-4
            - append exactly one new EA Index row:
              | EA-5 | synthesis (sections 5-6) | `feature/p5-task7-ea5-synthesis` | `a3419e9` | Entry 50 |
            - populate ## Prioritized Gap Report by REPLACING the exact line `Deferred to EA-5 synthesis.` with the full synthesis content specified in this prompt
            - populate ## Pre-existing Skip Analysis by REPLACING the exact line `Deferred to EA-5 synthesis.` with the full synthesis content specified in this prompt
            - append Entry 50 for this milestone using current ledger numbering
      Then STOP and WAIT for explicit Lead Architect (or Co-Lead reviewer) approval.
      Do NOT create the branch, write files, or run commands until the reviewer confirms that your recitation is correct.
    </instruction>
  </comprehension_gate>

  <milestone>
    <id>P5-TASK7-EA5</id>
    <title>Task 7 / EA-5: Prioritized Gap Report + Pre-existing Skip Analysis Synthesis</title>
    <type>DOCS-ONLY SYNTHESIS</type>
    <recommended_model>claude-opus-4.6</recommended_model>
    <model_rationale>Task 7 closing synthesis. Requires holistic judgment across eight service clusters' findings (policy_agent, assistant_orchestrator, semantic_router, ui_gateway, ui_shell, shared, launcher, integration) with prioritization discipline; no new code reads, pure synthesis of the existing canonical artifact plus two skip sites.</model_rationale>
    <branch>feature/p5-task7-ea5-synthesis</branch>
    <parent_branch>main</parent_branch>
    <parent_head>a3419e9</parent_head>
    <branch_command>git checkout -b feature/p5-task7-ea5-synthesis a3419e9</branch_command>
    <predecessor>Main HEAD a3419e9 is Task 7 EA-4 (Entry 49) merge 1f4aa20 plus two unrelated follow-up commits (4be41f7 archiving the EA-4 queue file, and a3419e9 fixing the Vikunja autostart script). Neither follow-up commit touches docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md or docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md. The canonical Task 7 artifact on main now contains sections 1-4 populated for all eight service clusters (policy_agent, assistant_orchestrator, semantic_router, ui_gateway, ui_shell, shared, launcher, integration) and sections 5-6 as stubs reading exactly "Deferred to EA-5 synthesis."</predecessor>
    <harness_declaration>NO_FULL_HARNESS</harness_declaration>

    <required_attachments>
      <file>.github/copilot-instructions.md</file>
      <file>docs/TEST_GOVERNANCE.md</file>
      <file>docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md</file>
      <file>docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md</file>
      <file>docs/P5_TASK7_SDO_CONTINUATION_v1.0.xml</file>
    </required_attachments>

    <objective>
      Close Task 7 by populating sections 5 and 6 of docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md through synthesis of the existing sections 1-4 and direct inspection of the two pre-existing skipped tests.
      EA-5 is limited to: (a) the canonical audit artifact itself, (b) docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md, and (c) read-only inspection of the two skipped-test sites for Section 6 evidence.
      EA-5 must NOT modify, re-read, or re-litigate any sections 1-4 content — that content is accepted on main.
      EA-5 must append ledger Entry 50 to docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md.
      No production files or test files may be modified.
    </objective>

    <artifact_state>
      <item>docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md on main contains populated sections 1-4 across eight service clusters.</item>
      <item>Section 5 (## Prioritized Gap Report) on main is a single-line stub: "Deferred to EA-5 synthesis."</item>
      <item>Section 6 (## Pre-existing Skip Analysis) on main is a single-line stub: "Deferred to EA-5 synthesis."</item>
      <item>EA-5 replaces each stub with its synthesized content and leaves sections 1-4 unchanged byte-for-byte except for the single new EA Index row.</item>
      <item>Entry 50 in docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md closes Task 7.</item>
    </artifact_state>

    <scope>
      Synthesis input (READ-ONLY, for analytical reasoning — do not modify):
      - docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md (all of sections 1-4 across eight service clusters)
      - docs/TEST_GOVERNANCE.md (governing standard for HIGH/MEDIUM/LOW prioritization)
      - docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md (Entries 39-49 for Task 7 historical context)

      Skip-site evidence (READ-ONLY — do not modify):
      - shared/tests/test_runtime_config.py (contains two pytest.skip sites at approximately lines 78 and 98, both guarding symlink creation on systems lacking elevated privileges)

      Synthesis output (WRITE):
      - docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md (Section 5 body, Section 6 body, and EA Index append only)
      - docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md (Entry 50 append only)

      Explicitly out of scope:
      - No re-reading of production source files under services/, shared/, launcher/.
      - No re-reading of test files other than the two skip sites in shared/tests/test_runtime_config.py.
      - No running of the test suite.
      - No changes to any file other than the two listed docs files.
    </scope>

    <work_items>
      <item id="WI-1">Read docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md sections 1-4 end-to-end and inventory every distinct finding recorded across the eight service clusters. Do not modify any content under sections 1-4.</item>
      <item id="WI-2">For each finding inventoried in WI-1, classify severity as HIGH, MEDIUM, or LOW according to the rubric in this prompt's prioritization_rubric block. Produce deduplicated cross-service groupings where a pattern (e.g. stale NPU nomenclature, missing fail-closed error-code assertions, exact-threshold boundary gaps, `constants.py` UNCOVERED status) recurs across clusters.</item>
      <item id="WI-3">Author ## Prioritized Gap Report body per the section_5_contract in this prompt. Keep the section strictly bounded by the eight service clusters already documented on main — introduce no new service or subsystem not already named in sections 1-4.</item>
      <item id="WI-4">Inspect the two pytest.skip sites in shared/tests/test_runtime_config.py (approximately lines 78 and 98) and record, for each: the test function name, the exact skip reason string, the production behavior each test is covering, and a disposition recommendation (FIX / REMOVE / KEEP).</item>
      <item id="WI-5">Author ## Pre-existing Skip Analysis body per the section_6_contract in this prompt. Do not introduce any skipped-test discussion for tests that are not in this explicit two-test set — the continuation XML locks the Section 6 scope at exactly two skipped tests.</item>
      <item id="WI-6">Preserve the existing EA Index rows (EA-1, EA-1 Correction, EA-2, EA-3, EA-4) exactly as they appear on main. Append exactly one new EA Index row: `| EA-5 | synthesis (sections 5-6) | \`feature/p5-task7-ea5-synthesis\` | \`a3419e9\` | Entry 50 |`.</item>
      <item id="WI-7">Append Entry 50 to docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md using current main numbering, declaring Task 7 COMPLETE.</item>
      <item id="WI-8">Enforce strict DOCS-ONLY hygiene: stage and commit only docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md and docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md. No other staged files are acceptable.</item>
      <item id="WI-9">If mid-session the synthesis cannot be completed without quality degradation (e.g. ambiguous prioritization for a cluster, insufficient context to make a KEEP/FIX/REMOVE determination on a skip), invoke Tier 3 fail-safe: produce a clearly labeled partial synthesis, record PARTIAL disposition in Entry 50, and recommend a re-scope rather than forcing a low-quality close-out.</item>
    </work_items>
  </milestone>

  <deliverable>
    <primary_artifact>
      Modify docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md on main-derived state. Preserve sections 1-4 and the existing EA Index rows exactly as-is. Replace the stub content of sections 5 and 6 with synthesized findings.
    </primary_artifact>

    <header_contract>
      Preserve the current top block exactly as it exists on main:
      - Title exactly: # Test Audit Findings
      - Keep:
        **Audit Type:** DOCS-ONLY qualitative audit — no production or test file modifications
        **Task:** P5-Task-7
        **Governance Reference:** `docs/TEST_GOVERNANCE.md`
        ### EA Index

      Preserve the existing EA Index rows exactly:
      - | EA-1 | policy_agent | `feature/p5-task7-ea1-policy-agent-audit` | `88b330d` | Entry 39 |
      - | EA-1 Correction | policy_agent | `feature/p5-task7-ea1-audit-correction` | `488b198` | Entry 40 |
      - | EA-2 | assistant_orchestrator, semantic_router | `feature/p5-task7-ea2-ao-sr-audit-correction` | `6ab1ece` | Entry 41 |
      - | EA-3 | ui_gateway, ui_shell | `feature/p5-task7-ea3-ui-gateway-ui-shell-audit` | `85cae8b` | Entry 48 |
      - | EA-4 | shared, launcher, tests/integration | `feature/p5-task7-ea4-shared-launcher-integration-audit` | `b858919` | Entry 49 |

      Append exactly one new row:
      - | EA-5 | synthesis (sections 5-6) | `feature/p5-task7-ea5-synthesis` | `a3419e9` | Entry 50 |
    </header_contract>

    <exact_structure>
      docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md must continue to contain exactly these 6 top-level sections in this exact order:
      1. ## Coverage Map
      2. ## Stale Test Inventory
      3. ## Assertion Quality Findings
      4. ## Boundary Violations
      5. ## Prioritized Gap Report
      6. ## Pre-existing Skip Analysis

      Under sections 1-4, the service subheadings on main are already:
      - ### policy_agent
      - ### assistant_orchestrator
      - ### semantic_router
      - ### ui_gateway
      - ### ui_shell
      - ### shared
      - ### launcher
      - ### integration

      EA-5 must NOT add, rename, remove, or reorder any service subheading under sections 1-4.
      EA-5 must NOT add any text to sections 1-4 other than preserving them byte-for-byte from main.
      The only changes to docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md are:
      - the appended EA-5 row in the EA Index table
      - the replacement of "Deferred to EA-5 synthesis." in Section 5 with the Section 5 synthesized content
      - the replacement of "Deferred to EA-5 synthesis." in Section 6 with the Section 6 synthesized content
    </exact_structure>

    <section_5_contract>
      Under ## Prioritized Gap Report, produce synthesized remediation items organized into three priority tiers using the exact subheading order and text:

      ### HIGH Priority

      ### MEDIUM Priority

      ### LOW Priority

      Each item under each priority tier is a bullet whose body begins with the source service cluster(s) in brackets (e.g. `[policy_agent]`, `[policy_agent, semantic_router]`, `[cross-service]`), followed by a one-sentence description of the remediation action, followed by a colon and a short justification citing the relevant section(s) by name (e.g. "Stale Test Inventory", "Boundary Violations") — do NOT cite sections by number.

      Deduplicate patterns that recur across clusters into a single cross-service item whenever the remediation action is substantially identical (e.g. stale NPU nomenclature across policy_agent, assistant_orchestrator, and semantic_router should collapse to one `[cross-service]` item referencing all affected clusters).

      Every item must reference findings that already appear in sections 1-4 of the canonical artifact on main. EA-5 must NOT introduce findings that are absent from sections 1-4.

      If any priority tier has no items, write exactly one line under its subheading:
      No HIGH priority items identified.
      (Adjust for MEDIUM and LOW accordingly.)

      End the section with a synthesis summary paragraph (2-4 sentences) titled:

      ### Synthesis Summary

      The Synthesis Summary must:
      - state the total remediation-item count across all tiers
      - name the dominant remediation themes (e.g. stale naming, missing error-code assertions, exact-threshold boundary gaps, `constants.py` coverage)
      - state whether Task 7 acceptance criteria are met or whether Tier 3 fail-safe is invoked
      - do NOT speculate about timelines, owners, or downstream tasks — remediation scheduling is outside Task 7 scope.
    </section_5_contract>

    <section_6_contract>
      Under ## Pre-existing Skip Analysis, synthesize an analysis for exactly the two pre-existing skipped tests in shared/tests/test_runtime_config.py (near lines 78 and 98; both guarded by symlink-privilege skip calls).

      The section must contain exactly these two subsections in this order:

      ### Skip 1 — shared/tests/test_runtime_config.py (first symlink skip site)

      ### Skip 2 — shared/tests/test_runtime_config.py (second symlink skip site)

      Each subsection must record:
      - Test function name (verbatim from the test file)
      - Skip reason string (verbatim from the pytest.skip call)
      - Production behavior covered (what production path does the test exercise when not skipped?)
      - Platform sensitivity (Windows vs. POSIX implications)
      - Disposition — exactly one of the following labels in bold:
        **KEEP** — rationale: ... (short paragraph)
        **FIX** — rationale: ... (short paragraph)
        **REMOVE** — rationale: ... (short paragraph)

      After both subsections, add a summary subsection titled:

      ### Skip Disposition Summary

      The Skip Disposition Summary must:
      - state each test's disposition (KEEP / FIX / REMOVE)
      - state the collective recommendation (e.g. both KEEP, or a mix)
      - do NOT introduce any additional skipped tests — Section 6 is locked to exactly these two sites

      If EA-5 concludes that the two skip sites require production or test file changes to resolve, Section 6 must recommend the change in narrative form only — EA-5 must NOT modify the test file or any production file.
    </section_6_contract>

    <prioritization_rubric>
      Use this rubric when assigning HIGH / MEDIUM / LOW in Section 5:

      HIGH:
      - Any finding under ## Boundary Violations that is a real boundary-correctness defect (not a preserved "no violations" sentence).
      - Any fail-closed path where a critical error code or security-relevant assertion is missing (e.g. missing error_code field assertion on fail-closed PA/AO paths, missing JWT validation negative case).
      - Any untested exact-threshold boundary at a critical decision surface (e.g. escalation floor 0.50 in policy_agent, PGOV leakage 0.85 in assistant_orchestrator, dual-gate thresholds in semantic_router).
      - Any stale nomenclature or stale architectural assumption that could mislead a future engineer into reintroducing retired hardware paths (e.g. ADR-011 NPU residues post-retirement).

      MEDIUM:
      - Coverage gaps labeled PARTIAL or THIN on modules with non-trivial logic (e.g. boot.py THIN, entrypoint.py PARTIAL, runtime_config.py PARTIAL, launcher/__main__.py PARTIAL).
      - Weak assertions flagged under ## Assertion Quality Findings that are not fail-closed-critical (e.g. field-presence-only checks in integration groups, circuit-breaker shallow assertions).
      - Redundant or partially-overlapping test files that add maintenance burden without unique coverage (e.g. test_adjudicator.py vs test_hybrid_adjudicator.py Group I overlap in policy_agent).

      LOW:
      - `constants.py` UNCOVERED-implicit status across multiple clusters (low ROI — constants are exercised transitively).
      - Stale naming that is not safety- or correctness-relevant (e.g. leftover comment references to retired model names that do not appear in active test identifiers).
      - Indirect-only coverage flags on modules whose behavior is adequately exercised via their callers (e.g. schemas/car.py indirect-only, session_panel.py indirect-only).

      When a finding could plausibly fall into two tiers, choose the HIGHER tier if any of the following applies: the finding touches a fail-closed path, a security assertion, an exact decision threshold, or an architectural-retirement violation. Otherwise choose the lower tier.
    </prioritization_rubric>

    <ledger_contract>
      Append Entry 50 to docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md using the existing ledger format.

      Required content:
      - Title: Entry 50 - Task 7/EA-5: Prioritized Gap Report + Pre-existing Skip Analysis Synthesis (COMPLETE)
      - Date: 2026-04-21 or actual execution date
      - Branch: feature/p5-task7-ea5-synthesis
      - Predecessor: Entry 49 - Task 7/EA-4: Shared + Launcher + Integration Audit (COMPLETE)
      - Type: AUDIT / DOCS-ONLY / SYNTHESIS
      - Disposition: COMPLETE (or PARTIAL if Tier 3 fail-safe triggered — in that case include a clear re-scope recommendation)
      - Summary: EA-5 closed Task 7 by synthesizing sections 1-4 across eight service clusters into the Prioritized Gap Report and analyzing the two pre-existing symlink-privilege skipped tests for the Pre-existing Skip Analysis; sections 1-4 preserved byte-for-byte; Task 7 audit is now complete.
      - Files: docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md and docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md only
      - Task 7 Closure Declaration: State explicitly that Task 7 is now COMPLETE and that the Prioritized Gap Report is the authoritative remediation backlog for any follow-on test-quality work.

      In Entry 50 summary and key findings:
      - do not use numbered section references such as Section 4, 5.3, or 5.4
      - use the exact section names (## Prioritized Gap Report, ## Pre-existing Skip Analysis, ## Boundary Violations, etc.) when cross-referencing
      - do not re-litigate accepted sections 1-4 content
      - do not create follow-on tasks in the ledger; the Prioritized Gap Report is the handoff, scheduling is outside Task 7
    </ledger_contract>
  </deliverable>

  <negative_constraints>
    <item>DO NOT modify any file under services/, shared/, launcher/, or tests/.</item>
    <item>DO NOT modify docs/TEST_GOVERNANCE.md.</item>
    <item>DO NOT modify docs/IMPLEMENTATION_PLAN.md.</item>
    <item>DO NOT modify docs/P5_TASK7_SDO_CONTINUATION_v1.0.xml.</item>
    <item>DO NOT modify any file under docs/scheduled/.</item>
    <item>DO NOT add any content to sections 1-4 of docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md — they must remain byte-for-byte identical to main except for the single new EA Index row.</item>
    <item>DO NOT alter, reformat, or reorder any existing service subheading under sections 1-4.</item>
    <item>DO NOT alter the existing EA Index rows for EA-1, EA-1 Correction, EA-2, EA-3, or EA-4.</item>
    <item>DO NOT add top-level sections beyond the 6 required sections.</item>
    <item>DO NOT rename any of the 6 required top-level sections.</item>
    <item>DO NOT add numbered prefixes to section headers (## 5. Prioritized Gap Report is forbidden).</item>
    <item>DO NOT introduce remediation items in Section 5 that are not traceable to findings already recorded in sections 1-4.</item>
    <item>DO NOT introduce skipped-test analyses in Section 6 for tests that are not in the explicit two-site set in shared/tests/test_runtime_config.py.</item>
    <item>DO NOT propose fixes, patches, or code changes inline — Section 5 items and Section 6 dispositions are recommendations only.</item>
    <item>DO NOT speculate about remediation scheduling, owners, or downstream task identifiers — scheduling is outside Task 7 scope.</item>
    <item>DO NOT run pytest, coverage tooling, or install dependencies.</item>
    <item>DO NOT use git add .</item>
    <item>DO NOT touch unrelated pre-existing untracked files in the worktree.</item>
  </negative_constraints>

  <context_notes>
    <note id="CN-1" title="Audit standard">
      docs/TEST_GOVERNANCE.md is the governing standard for this audit. Use its scope definitions,
      marker policy, boundary rules, and qualitative coverage expectations when calibrating HIGH/MEDIUM/LOW priority.
    </note>

    <note id="CN-2" title="Synthesis, not re-audit">
      EA-5 is a synthesis milestone. Sections 1-4 are accepted on main and must not be re-litigated.
      If EA-5 identifies what it believes is a missing finding in sections 1-4, that belongs in a follow-on
      remediation task — NOT in sections 1-4 of this artifact.
    </note>

    <note id="CN-3" title="Current artifact is canonical">
      docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md on main is the canonical shared Task 7 artifact.
      EA-5 must extend it in-place by populating only sections 5 and 6 and by appending one EA Index row.
    </note>

    <note id="CN-4" title="Prioritization discipline">
      Oversight includes an independent Co-Lead completion review under the DEC-12 peer-review lattice.
      HIGH priority items must meet the rubric criteria (fail-closed, security, critical threshold, or architectural-retirement residue).
      Inflating MEDIUM items to HIGH to appear thorough is a quality defect.
      Collapsing HIGH items to MEDIUM to appear conservative is also a quality defect.
    </note>

    <note id="CN-5" title="Skip scope is locked at two">
      The continuation XML (Section 6 contract) locks Section 6 scope at exactly two pre-existing skipped tests.
      These are the two symlink-privilege skips in shared/tests/test_runtime_config.py.
      If EA-5 encounters additional skipped tests during incidental reading, it must NOT extend Section 6 to include them.
      Out-of-scope skipped tests (if any) should be recorded in Entry 50 as an observation, not added to Section 6.
    </note>

    <note id="CN-6" title="Out-of-scope untracked files already present">
      The worktree may contain unrelated untracked artifacts (e.g. tools/scheduled-tasks/logs/, tools/fleet_observability/*.flag, scheduled state.json edits).
      Do not touch, stage, rename, or delete them. They are outside this milestone.
    </note>

    <note id="CN-7" title="Tier 3 fail-safe remains first-class">
      If the synthesis cannot be completed without quality degradation (e.g. ambiguous severity for an entire cluster, insufficient evidence to make a KEEP/FIX/REMOVE determination on a skip), invoke Tier 3 fail-safe:
      deliver an honest partial synthesis covering the tiers and skips for which the evidence is strong,
      record PARTIAL disposition in Entry 50, and recommend a re-scope (e.g. EA-5a Prioritized Gap Report only; EA-5b Skip Analysis only).
      Given this is Task 7's closing milestone, forcing a weak close-out is the worst outcome.
    </note>

    <note id="CN-8" title="No follow-on task scheduling in this milestone">
      The Prioritized Gap Report IS the handoff. It enumerates what remediation work exists and its priority.
      It does NOT schedule that work, assign it, or create follow-on Vikunja tickets.
      Any scheduling is a Lead Architect decision that lives outside Task 7.
    </note>
  </context_notes>

  <quality_gate>
    <gate id="COMPILE" order="1">
      <command>N/A - DOCS-ONLY synthesis milestone</command>
      <criteria>No Python files may be created or modified in this milestone.</criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="TEST" order="2">
      <command>N/A - DOCS-ONLY synthesis milestone</command>
      <criteria>
        Do not run pytest as a standard gate for this slice.
        Section 6 evidence comes from read-only inspection of shared/tests/test_runtime_config.py at the two skip sites.
        If a targeted read-only command is used to confirm a skip reason string verbatim, report it explicitly.
      </criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="ORACLE_1" order="3">
      <command>Manual synthesis completion against sections 1-4 and the two skip sites</command>
      <criteria>
        All eight service clusters' findings in sections 1-4 are represented or explicitly deduplicated under cross-service items in Section 5.
        Both skip sites in shared/tests/test_runtime_config.py are analyzed in Section 6 with verbatim skip reason strings.
        If a Tier 3 fail-safe is invoked, clearly label which clusters or which skip did NOT reach a quality synthesis in Entry 50 PARTIAL disposition.
      </criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="ORACLE_2" order="4">
      <command>Review docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md structure and header</command>
      <criteria>
        The top title remains exactly # Test Audit Findings.
        The document still contains the same 6 required top-level sections in the same order.
        Sections 1-4 contain the same eight service subheadings in the same order as on main, with content byte-for-byte preserved.
        The existing five EA Index rows remain intact and exactly one EA-5 row is appended.
        Sections 5 and 6 no longer contain the literal string "Deferred to EA-5 synthesis." — that stub is fully replaced.
      </criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="ORACLE_3" order="5">
      <command>Review Section 5 structure and rubric compliance</command>
      <criteria>
        ## Prioritized Gap Report contains exactly ### HIGH Priority, ### MEDIUM Priority, ### LOW Priority subheadings in that order, followed by ### Synthesis Summary.
        Every Section 5 bullet begins with a service cluster bracket prefix and references a finding from sections 1-4.
        No numbered section references (no "Section 4", no "5.3") appear anywhere in Section 5.
        HIGH-tier assignments meet the rubric criteria; no inflation or deflation is evident on spot-check.
      </criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="ORACLE_4" order="6">
      <command>Review Section 6 structure and skip scope</command>
      <criteria>
        ## Pre-existing Skip Analysis contains exactly ### Skip 1, ### Skip 2, and ### Skip Disposition Summary subheadings in that order.
        Each skip subsection records a verbatim skip reason string, the production behavior covered, platform sensitivity, and one of KEEP / FIX / REMOVE in bold.
        Section 6 analyzes exactly the two shared/tests/test_runtime_config.py skip sites — no additional skipped tests are introduced.
      </criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="ORACLE_5" order="7">
      <command>Review docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md metadata</command>
      <criteria>
        Entry 50 exists and matches the required title, date, predecessor (Entry 49), type (AUDIT / DOCS-ONLY / SYNTHESIS), and disposition.
        Entry 50 does not use numbered section references.
        Entry 50 explicitly declares Task 7 COMPLETE.
        If Tier 3 fail-safe is invoked, Entry 50 carries PARTIAL disposition and a clear re-scope recommendation.
      </criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="ORACLE_6" order="8">
      <command>git diff --staged --name-only a3419e9</command>
      <criteria>
        Output contains ONLY:
        - docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md
        - docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md
      </criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="ORACLE_7" order="9">
      <command>Tier 3 fail-safe check</command>
      <criteria>
        If the synthesis cannot be completed without degraded quality, STOP,
        leave a clearly labeled partial report, record PARTIAL status in Entry 50,
        and recommend a re-scope instead of forcing a weak close-out.
        EA-5 is Task 7's closing milestone — honest partial is strictly better than forced weak close-out.
      </criteria>
    </gate>
  </quality_gate>

  <verification>
    <instruction>
      The Lead Architect will verify this milestone using terminal commands only.
      Your final EA response must report results that these commands can confirm.
    </instruction>

    <commands>
      <command>git branch --show-current</command>
      <expected>feature/p5-task7-ea5-synthesis</expected>

      <command>git log --oneline -1</command>
      <expected>Single EA-5 synthesis commit on the feature branch</expected>

      <command>git diff a3419e9 --name-only</command>
      <expected>
        docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md
        docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md
      </expected>

      <command>git diff a3419e9 --name-only | Select-String "\.py$"</command>
      <expected>No output</expected>

      <command>Select-String -Path docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md -Pattern "^# Test Audit Findings$","^### EA Index$","^## ","^### policy_agent$","^### assistant_orchestrator$","^### semantic_router$","^### ui_gateway$","^### ui_shell$","^### shared$","^### launcher$","^### integration$","^### HIGH Priority$","^### MEDIUM Priority$","^### LOW Priority$","^### Synthesis Summary$","^### Skip 1","^### Skip 2","^### Skip Disposition Summary$"</command>
      <expected>
        Shows the preserved multi-EA header, the 6 required top-level sections, all eight preserved service subheadings under sections 1-4, the four new Section 5 subheadings, and the three new Section 6 subheadings.
      </expected>

      <command>Select-String -Path docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md -Pattern "Deferred to EA-5 synthesis"</command>
      <expected>No output — both stubs are fully replaced.</expected>

      <command>Select-String -Path docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md -Pattern "Entry 50","Type: AUDIT / DOCS-ONLY / SYNTHESIS","Disposition: (COMPLETE|PARTIAL)","Task 7 (is now |)COMPLETE" | Select-Object -First 8</command>
      <expected>Ledger contains contract-compliant Entry 50 with Task 7 closure declaration.</expected>
    </commands>
  </verification>

  <commit_template>
    <message>
Task 7 EA-5: synthesize Prioritized Gap Report + Pre-existing Skip Analysis

- Populated ## Prioritized Gap Report with HIGH/MEDIUM/LOW tiers synthesized from sections 1-4 across eight service clusters
- Populated ## Pre-existing Skip Analysis with KEEP/FIX/REMOVE dispositions for both shared/tests/test_runtime_config.py symlink skip sites
- Preserved sections 1-4 byte-for-byte; appended EA-5 row to the EA Index
- Added Entry 50 in Post-Operational Maturation Ledger declaring Task 7 COMPLETE
    </message>
  </commit_template>

</execution_prompt>
