<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<execution_prompt version="1.0" task="P5-Task-7" milestone="EA-4" authored="2026-04-21" sdo_firing="post-EA-3-merge" staging="awaiting-colead-completion-review">

  <comprehension_gate>
    <instruction>
      MANDATORY FIRST ACTION: Before any branch creation, file edits, or commands, read this entire prompt and all required attachments in full.
      Then present a structured comprehension summary to the Lead Architect (or the Co-Lead reviewer under the DEC-12 peer-review lattice) covering:
        (a) milestone objective in your own words
        (b) work items with 1 sentence each
        (c) files to READ and files to WRITE
        (d) exact structural requirements for docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md and docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md
        (e) ORACLE strategy for this DOCS-ONLY audit milestone
        (f) risks or ambiguities (specifically: 20-file read-scope is the tightest EA-N scope to date; Tier-3 fail-safe is expected to be considered)
        (g) EXACT deliverable structure, recited VERBATIM from this prompt:
            - branch to create: feature/p5-task7-ea4-shared-launcher-integration-audit from main at b858919
            - files to WRITE: docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md and docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md only
            - docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md must retain exactly these 6 top-level sections in this order:
              1. ## Coverage Map
              2. ## Stale Test Inventory
              3. ## Assertion Quality Findings
              4. ## Boundary Violations
              5. ## Prioritized Gap Report
              6. ## Pre-existing Skip Analysis
            - under sections 1-4, preserve ### policy_agent, ### assistant_orchestrator, ### semantic_router, ### ui_gateway, and ### ui_shell, then append ### shared, ### launcher, and ### integration in that order
            - preserve the existing header and four EA Index rows from main exactly, then append exactly one new row:
              | EA-4 | shared, launcher, tests/integration | `feature/p5-task7-ea4-shared-launcher-integration-audit` | `b858919` | Entry 49 |
            - sections 5 and 6 remain exactly: Deferred to EA-5 synthesis.
            - append Entry 49 for this milestone
      Then STOP and WAIT for explicit Lead Architect approval.
      Do NOT create the branch, write files, or run commands until the Lead Architect confirms that your recitation is correct.
    </instruction>
  </comprehension_gate>

  <milestone>
    <id>P5-TASK7-EA4</id>
    <title>Task 7 / EA-4: Shared + Launcher + Integration Audit</title>
    <type>DOCS-ONLY AUDIT</type>
    <recommended_model>claude-opus-4.6</recommended_model>
    <model_rationale>Largest EA-N read-scope in Task 7 (20 files across three scope clusters); requires careful multi-subsection appends to a shared artifact under strict taxonomy and numbering discipline.</model_rationale>
    <branch>feature/p5-task7-ea4-shared-launcher-integration-audit</branch>
    <parent_branch>main</parent_branch>
    <parent_head>b858919</parent_head>
    <branch_command>git checkout -b feature/p5-task7-ea4-shared-launcher-integration-audit b858919</branch_command>
    <predecessor>Main HEAD b858919 is the Task 7 EA-3 + fleet-install + DEC-12 + observability A-D + trusted_scope rollup merge (Entry 48 on main, 2026-04-21). The accepted Task 7 artifact on main now contains policy_agent, assistant_orchestrator, semantic_router, ui_gateway, and ui_shell findings (EA-1 through EA-3, Entries 39-41 + Entry 48) and must be extended without structural drift.</predecessor>
    <harness_declaration>NO_FULL_HARNESS</harness_declaration>

    <required_attachments>
      <file>.github/copilot-instructions.md</file>
      <file>docs/TEST_GOVERNANCE.md</file>
      <file>docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md</file>
      <file>docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md</file>
      <file>docs/P5_TASK7_SDO_CONTINUATION_v1.0.xml</file>
    </required_attachments>

    <objective>
      Audit the shared/, launcher/, and tests/integration/ test suites against docs/TEST_GOVERNANCE.md and append findings to the canonical Task 7 artifact.
      EA-4 is limited to shared/**, launcher/**, and tests/integration/**.
      It must answer the four Task 7 audit questions for those three scope clusters only: coverage gaps, stale/dead tests, assertion quality, and boundary correctness.
      It must append ledger Entry 49 to docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md.
      No production files or test files may be changed.
    </objective>

    <artifact_state>
      <item>The current main artifact is already populated for policy_agent, assistant_orchestrator, semantic_router, ui_gateway, and ui_shell.</item>
      <item>EA-4 must preserve all accepted prior content from main and append shared, launcher, and integration findings only.</item>
      <item>Section 4 (Boundary Violations) must be kept limited to true boundary-correctness findings. The tests/integration cluster is expected to be dominated by intentional integration-boundary behavior; document the intent rather than re-framing coverage gaps as boundary findings.</item>
      <item>Sections 5 and 6 remain reserved for EA-5 synthesis.</item>
    </artifact_state>

    <scope>
      Re-read exactly these in-scope source and test files, excluding __init__.py from coverage counts:

      shared production files:
      - shared/constants.py
      - shared/crypto/jwt_validator.py
      - shared/ipc/protocol.py
      - shared/ipc/vsock.py
      - shared/models/weight_integrity.py
      - shared/runtime_config.py
      - shared/schemas/car.py

      shared test files:
      - shared/tests/test_ipc_protocol.py
      - shared/tests/test_ipc_transport.py
      - shared/tests/test_jwt_validator.py
      - shared/tests/test_runtime_config.py
      - shared/tests/test_weight_integrity.py

      launcher production files:
      - launcher/__main__.py
      - launcher/guest_deploy.py
      - launcher/vm_manager.py

      launcher test files:
      - launcher/tests/test_guest_deploy.py
      - launcher/tests/test_launcher.py
      - launcher/tests/test_vm_manager.py

      integration test files (cross-service — no dedicated production directory):
      - tests/integration/test_p110_end_to_end.py
      - tests/integration/test_p114_ui_end_to_end.py
    </scope>

    <work_items>
      <item id="WI-1">Re-read all 10 production files and all 10 test files in scope before changing the artifact.</item>
      <item id="WI-2">Preserve the accepted header and existing service content in docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md, then append exactly one EA-4 row to the EA Index.</item>
      <item id="WI-3">Append shared findings under sections 1-4 only, after the existing ui_shell subsection in each populated section.</item>
      <item id="WI-4">Append launcher findings under sections 1-4 only, after the shared subsection in each populated section.</item>
      <item id="WI-5">Append integration findings under sections 1-4 only, after the launcher subsection in each populated section. For Coverage Map specifically: there is no dedicated production directory; describe which cross-service paths each integration test exercises and record coverage adequacy against that cross-service surface (not against a single production file).</item>
      <item id="WI-6">Audit all three scope clusters for stale or dead tests, including superseded import paths, obsolete architectural assumptions (e.g. ADR-011 NPU→GPU retirement, ADR-012 Qwen3-14B unification), and tests whose stated purpose no longer matches production behavior.</item>
      <item id="WI-7">Audit all three scope clusters for weak assertions and tests that prove too little.</item>
      <item id="WI-8">Audit all three scope clusters for true boundary-correctness issues only and keep non-boundary coverage gaps out of Section 4. Specifically for tests/integration: intentional integration-boundary behavior is NOT a violation — only flag tests whose boundary classification is demonstrably wrong (e.g. a test placed in tests/integration but executing no cross-service interaction, or a test placed elsewhere but exercising live cross-service I/O).</item>
      <item id="WI-9">Append Entry 49 to docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md using current main numbering.</item>
      <item id="WI-10">Enforce strict DOCS-ONLY hygiene: stage and commit only the two allowed docs files.</item>
      <item id="WI-11">Use Tier 3 fail-safe if the assigned scope cannot be completed without quality degradation. At 20 files this is the tightest EA-N scope in Task 7; honest partial completion with a documented re-scope recommendation is preferable to rushed low-quality findings.</item>
    </work_items>
  </milestone>

  <deliverable>
    <primary_artifact>
      Modify docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md on main-derived state. Preserve accepted policy_agent, assistant_orchestrator, semantic_router, ui_gateway, and ui_shell content from main exactly as-is, except for the minimal EA Index append.
    </primary_artifact>

    <header_contract>
      Preserve the current top block exactly as it exists on main:
      - Title exactly: # Test Audit Findings
      - Keep:
        **Audit Type:** DOCS-ONLY qualitative audit — no production or test file modifications
        **Task:** P5-Task-7
        **Governance Reference:** `docs/TEST_GOVERNANCE.md`
        ### EA Index

      Preserve the existing EA Index rows exactly:
      - | EA-1 | policy_agent | `feature/p5-task7-ea1-policy-agent-audit` | `88b330d` | Entry 39 |
      - | EA-1 Correction | policy_agent | `feature/p5-task7-ea1-audit-correction` | `488b198` | Entry 40 |
      - | EA-2 | assistant_orchestrator, semantic_router | `feature/p5-task7-ea2-ao-sr-audit-correction` | `6ab1ece` | Entry 41 |
      - | EA-3 | ui_gateway, ui_shell | `feature/p5-task7-ea3-ui-gateway-ui-shell-audit` | `85cae8b` | Entry 48 |

      Append exactly one new row:
      - | EA-4 | shared, launcher, tests/integration | `feature/p5-task7-ea4-shared-launcher-integration-audit` | `b858919` | Entry 49 |
    </header_contract>

    <exact_structure>
      docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md must continue to contain exactly these 6 top-level sections in this exact order:
      1. ## Coverage Map
      2. ## Stale Test Inventory
      3. ## Assertion Quality Findings
      4. ## Boundary Violations
      5. ## Prioritized Gap Report
      6. ## Pre-existing Skip Analysis

      Under sections 1-4 only, the service headings after EA-4 are:
      - ### policy_agent
      - ### assistant_orchestrator
      - ### semantic_router
      - ### ui_gateway
      - ### ui_shell
      - ### shared
      - ### launcher
      - ### integration

      Preserve the existing five service subsections from main exactly as they are.
      Append new shared content after ui_shell within each populated section.
      Append new launcher content after shared within each populated section.
      Append new integration content after launcher within each populated section.
      Sections 5 and 6 must remain exactly:
      - Deferred to EA-5 synthesis.
    </exact_structure>

    <coverage_contract>
      Under ## Coverage Map:
      - preserve the accepted policy_agent, assistant_orchestrator, semantic_router, ui_gateway, and ui_shell content already on main
      - append shared findings under ### shared
      - append launcher findings under ### launcher
      - append integration findings under ### integration
      - for shared and launcher: map every production file in scope to its corresponding test file(s)
      - for integration: for each test file, record which cross-service code paths it exercises (e.g. policy_agent + assistant_orchestrator round-trip, ui_gateway + ui_shell streaming path) and record qualitative coverage adequacy against that cross-service surface
      - record qualitative coverage adequacy and notable coverage gaps
      - if a production file has only indirect or incidental coverage, say so explicitly
    </coverage_contract>

    <stale_contract>
      Under ## Stale Test Inventory:
      - append shared stale findings under ### shared
      - append launcher stale findings under ### launcher
      - append integration stale findings under ### integration
      - if any of the three has no stale findings, state that explicitly
      - include stale naming, dead imports, superseded assumptions, or tests whose stated purpose no longer matches current implementation
      - be especially alert for ADR-011 (NPU retired; LLM inference on GPU) and ADR-012 (Qwen3-14B unified model) residues in these scope clusters
    </stale_contract>

    <assertion_contract>
      Under ## Assertion Quality Findings:
      - append shared findings under ### shared
      - append launcher findings under ### launcher
      - append integration findings under ### integration
      - identify weak assertions, tests that only prove non-crash, overreliance on implementation details, and assertions too shallow to catch real regressions
      - for integration tests specifically, flag tests that merely confirm the pipeline ran without crashing versus tests that assert observable cross-service outcomes
      - if any of the three has no material assertion-quality issues, state that explicitly
    </assertion_contract>

    <boundary_contract>
      Under ## Boundary Violations:
      - preserve ### policy_agent, ### assistant_orchestrator, ### semantic_router, ### ui_gateway, and ### ui_shell exactly as they exist on main
      - append ### shared
      - append ### launcher
      - append ### integration

      Boundary-correctness means only:
      - real socket connections
      - real filesystem writes beyond isolated scaffolding
      - dependence on live services or hardware
      - tests that should really be integration tests rather than service-level unit tests
      - tests that are placed under tests/integration/ but perform no genuine cross-service interaction

      The following do NOT belong in this section:
      - exact numeric threshold coverage gaps
      - missing state-transition branches that are really coverage findings
      - stale nomenclature
      - weak assertions
      - intentional, marker-declared integration-boundary behavior in tests/integration/ (that is the designed contract, not a violation)

      Borderline cases must be justified explicitly.
      Self-contained temporary-file scaffolding or controlled test doubles do not automatically count as boundary violations.

      If shared has no true boundary violations, write exactly:
      No material boundary violations identified for shared.

      If launcher has no true boundary violations, write exactly:
      No material boundary violations identified for launcher.

      If integration has no true boundary violations, write exactly:
      No material boundary violations identified for integration.
    </boundary_contract>

    <ledger_contract>
      Append Entry 49 to docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md using the existing ledger format.

      Required content:
      - Title: Entry 49 - Task 7/EA-4: Shared + Launcher + Integration Audit (COMPLETE)
      - Date: 2026-04-21 or actual execution date
      - Branch: feature/p5-task7-ea4-shared-launcher-integration-audit
      - Predecessor: Entry 48 - Task 7/EA-3: UI Gateway + UI Shell Audit (COMPLETE)
      - Type: AUDIT / DOCS-ONLY
      - Disposition: COMPLETE (or PARTIAL if Tier 3 fail-safe triggered — in that case include a clear re-scope recommendation)
      - Summary: EA-4 completed against post-EA-3 main; shared, launcher, and integration findings appended to docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md; existing prior-service findings preserved; sections 5-6 remain deferred to EA-5
      - Files: docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md and docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md only

      In Entry 49 summary and key findings:
      - do not use numbered section references such as Section 4, 5.3, or 5.4
      - do not describe generic coverage gaps as boundary tests
      - do not describe intentional cross-service behavior in tests/integration/ as boundary violations
    </ledger_contract>
  </deliverable>

  <negative_constraints>
    <item>DO NOT modify any file under shared/.</item>
    <item>DO NOT modify any file under launcher/.</item>
    <item>DO NOT modify any file under tests/integration/.</item>
    <item>DO NOT modify docs/TEST_GOVERNANCE.md.</item>
    <item>DO NOT modify docs/IMPLEMENTATION_PLAN.md.</item>
    <item>DO NOT rewrite or re-litigate accepted policy_agent, assistant_orchestrator, semantic_router, ui_gateway, or ui_shell findings from main.</item>
    <item>DO NOT add top-level sections beyond the 6 required sections.</item>
    <item>DO NOT rename any of the 6 required top-level sections.</item>
    <item>DO NOT add numbered prefixes to section headers (## 1. Coverage Map is forbidden).</item>
    <item>DO NOT populate ## Prioritized Gap Report with findings. Leave it exactly: Deferred to EA-5 synthesis.</item>
    <item>DO NOT populate ## Pre-existing Skip Analysis with findings. Leave it exactly: Deferred to EA-5 synthesis.</item>
    <item>DO NOT place generic coverage gaps or weak assertions under ## Boundary Violations.</item>
    <item>DO NOT flag intentional, marker-declared integration-boundary behavior in tests/integration/ as a boundary violation — the integration marker is the designed contract.</item>
    <item>DO NOT use git add .</item>
    <item>DO NOT run coverage tooling or install dependencies.</item>
    <item>DO NOT touch unrelated pre-existing untracked files in the worktree.</item>
  </negative_constraints>

  <context_notes>
    <note id="CN-1" title="Audit standard">
      docs/TEST_GOVERNANCE.md is the governing standard for this audit. Use its scope definitions,
      marker policy, boundary rules, and qualitative coverage expectations as the audit rubric.
    </note>

    <note id="CN-2" title="Qualitative audit only">
      Numeric coverage tooling is out of scope. This audit is based on careful code-to-test mapping
      and governance alignment, not coverage percentages.
    </note>

    <note id="CN-3" title="Current artifact is canonical">
      docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md on main is now the canonical shared Task 7 artifact.
      EA-4 must extend it in-place without disturbing accepted prior content.
    </note>

    <note id="CN-4" title="Boundary taxonomy must remain strict">
      Oversight includes an independent Co-Lead completion review under the DEC-12 peer-review lattice.
      Findings placed under ## Boundary Violations must be true boundary-correctness issues, not mislabeled coverage or assertion gaps.
      Integration tests' intentional cross-service behavior is not a violation — that is their designed contract.
    </note>

    <note id="CN-5" title="Diagnosis only">
      This is a diagnosis-only audit. The EA must not fix any finding, add any test, or modify any source/test file.
    </note>

    <note id="CN-6" title="Out-of-scope untracked files already present">
      The worktree may contain unrelated untracked artifacts (e.g. tools/scheduled-tasks/logs/, scheduled state.json edits).
      Do not touch, stage, rename, or delete them. They are outside this milestone.
    </note>

    <note id="CN-7" title="20-file read-scope is the tightest EA-N scope">
      EA-4 reads 10 production files and 10 test files across three scope clusters — the largest EA-N scope in Task 7.
      If mid-session the audit cannot be completed without quality degradation, invoke Tier 3 fail-safe:
      deliver a honest partial report across as many files as have been audited to quality, record PARTIAL disposition in Entry 49,
      and recommend a re-scope (e.g. EA-4a shared + launcher / EA-4b integration) rather than forcing a weak close-out.
    </note>

    <note id="CN-8" title="Integration coverage reporting is cross-service">
      Unlike EA-1..EA-3, the integration cluster has no single production directory to map tests against.
      Under ### integration / Coverage Map, describe what cross-service code paths each integration test exercises
      and evaluate coverage adequacy against those cross-service surfaces. Do not leave the subsection blank.
    </note>
  </context_notes>

  <quality_gate>
    <gate id="COMPILE" order="1">
      <command>N/A - DOCS-ONLY audit milestone</command>
      <criteria>No Python files may be created or modified in this milestone.</criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="TEST" order="2">
      <command>N/A - DOCS-ONLY audit milestone</command>
      <criteria>
        Do not run pytest as a standard gate for this slice.
        Use file inspection as the primary evidence source.
        If you choose to run a targeted read-only command to confirm a suspected stale reference or boundary claim, report it explicitly.
      </criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="ORACLE_1" order="3">
      <command>Manual audit completion against all 10 production files and all 10 test files in scope</command>
      <criteria>
        All 7 shared production files, all 5 shared test files,
        all 3 launcher production files, all 3 launcher test files,
        and all 2 integration test files are evaluated.
        If a Tier 3 fail-safe is invoked, clearly label which files were NOT evaluated to quality in Entry 49 PARTIAL disposition.
      </criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="ORACLE_2" order="4">
      <command>Review docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md structure and header</command>
      <criteria>
        The top title remains exactly # Test Audit Findings.
        The document still contains the same 6 required top-level sections in the same order.
        Sections 1-4 contain only ### policy_agent, ### assistant_orchestrator, ### semantic_router, ### ui_gateway, ### ui_shell, ### shared, ### launcher, and ### integration service headings.
        The existing four EA Index rows remain intact and exactly one EA-4 row is appended.
        Sections 5 and 6 remain exactly: Deferred to EA-5 synthesis.
      </criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="ORACLE_3" order="5">
      <command>Review section placement and boundary taxonomy</command>
      <criteria>
        shared, launcher, and integration findings appear only under sections 1-4.
        shared, launcher, and integration boundary content contains only true boundary-correctness findings.
        If any of the three has no true boundary violations, its subsection contains the exact required no-violation sentence for that cluster.
        Integration tests' intentional cross-service behavior is NOT flagged under Boundary Violations.
      </criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="ORACLE_4" order="6">
      <command>Review docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md metadata</command>
      <criteria>
        Entry 49 exists and matches the required title, date, predecessor (Entry 48), type, and disposition.
        Entry 49 does not use numbered section references and does not mislabel generic coverage gaps as boundary tests.
        If Tier 3 fail-safe is invoked, Entry 49 carries PARTIAL disposition and a clear re-scope recommendation.
      </criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="ORACLE_5" order="7">
      <command>git diff --staged --name-only b858919</command>
      <criteria>
        Output contains ONLY:
        - docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md
        - docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md
      </criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="ORACLE_6" order="8">
      <command>Tier 3 fail-safe check</command>
      <criteria>
        If the audit cannot be completed without degraded quality, STOP,
        leave a clearly labeled partial report, record PARTIAL status in Entry 49,
        and recommend a re-scope instead of forcing a weak close-out.
        Given the 20-file scope, the Tier 3 branch is a first-class expected outcome, not a failure.
      </criteria>
    </gate>
  </quality_gate>

  <verification>
    <instruction>
      The Lead Architect will verify this milestone using terminal commands only.
      Your final EA response must report results that these commands can confirm.
    </instruction>

    <commands>
      <command>git branch --show-current</command>
      <expected>feature/p5-task7-ea4-shared-launcher-integration-audit</expected>

      <command>git log --oneline -1</command>
      <expected>Single EA-4 audit commit on the feature branch</expected>

      <command>git diff b858919 --name-only</command>
      <expected>
        docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md
        docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md
      </expected>

      <command>git diff b858919 --name-only | Select-String "\.py$"</command>
      <expected>No output</expected>

      <command>Select-String -Path docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md -Pattern "^# Test Audit Findings$","^### EA Index$","^## ","^### policy_agent$","^### assistant_orchestrator$","^### semantic_router$","^### ui_gateway$","^### ui_shell$","^### shared$","^### launcher$","^### integration$","Deferred to EA-5 synthesis"</command>
      <expected>
        Shows the preserved multi-EA header, the 6 required top-level sections, the eight allowed service headings (five preserved + three newly appended),
        and the unchanged deferred placeholders.
      </expected>

      <command>Select-String -Path docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md -Pattern "Entry 49","Type: AUDIT / DOCS-ONLY","Disposition: (COMPLETE|PARTIAL)" | Select-Object -First 6</command>
      <expected>Ledger contains contract-compliant Entry 49 for EA-4 on current main.</expected>
    </commands>
  </verification>

  <commit_template>
    <message>
Task 7 EA-4: append shared + launcher + integration audit

- Appended shared, launcher, and integration findings to docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md
- Preserved accepted prior-service findings and deferred sections 5-6 to EA-5
- Added Entry 49 in Post-Operational Maturation Ledger
    </message>
  </commit_template>

</execution_prompt>
