<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<execution_prompt version="1.0" task="P5-Task-7" milestone="EA-2">

  <comprehension_gate>
    <instruction>
      MANDATORY FIRST ACTION: Before any branch creation, file edits, or commands, read this entire prompt and all required attachments in full.
      Then present a structured comprehension summary to the Lead Architect covering:
        (a) milestone objective in your own words
        (b) work items with 1 sentence each
        (c) files to READ and files to WRITE
        (d) ORACLE strategy for this DOCS-ONLY milestone
        (e) risks or ambiguities
        (f) EXACT deliverable structure, recited VERBATIM from this prompt:
            - branch to create: feature/p5-task7-ea2-ao-sr-audit from main at 488b198
            - files to WRITE: docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md and docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md only
            - docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md must retain exactly these 6 top-level sections in this order:
              1. ## Coverage Map
              2. ## Stale Test Inventory
              3. ## Assertion Quality Findings
              4. ## Boundary Violations
              5. ## Prioritized Gap Report
              6. ## Pre-existing Skip Analysis
            - append assistant_orchestrator and semantic_router findings to sections 1-4 only
            - leave sections 5 and 6 exactly: Deferred to EA-5 synthesis.
      Then STOP and WAIT for explicit Lead Architect approval.
      Do NOT create the branch, write files, or run commands until the Lead Architect confirms that your recitation is correct.
    </instruction>
  </comprehension_gate>

  <milestone>
    <id>P5-TASK7-EA2</id>
    <title>Task 7 / EA-2: Assistant Orchestrator + Semantic Router Audit</title>
    <type>DOCS-ONLY AUDIT</type>
    <recommended_model>claude-opus-4.6</recommended_model>
    <model_rationale>Constraint-heavy DOCS-ONLY task. L-12 showed that stronger structural compliance controls are needed.</model_rationale>
    <branch>feature/p5-task7-ea2-ao-sr-audit</branch>
    <parent_branch>main</parent_branch>
    <parent_head>488b198</parent_head>
    <branch_command>git checkout -b feature/p5-task7-ea2-ao-sr-audit 488b198</branch_command>
    <predecessor>Task 7 / EA-1 merged to main via ff54654. Current main HEAD 488b198 also includes the separate governance merge.</predecessor>
    <harness_declaration>NO_FULL_HARNESS</harness_declaration>

    <objective>
      Audit the assistant_orchestrator and semantic_router test suites against docs/TEST_GOVERNANCE.md and append findings to the merged Task 7 artifact at docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md.
      EA-2 is limited to services/assistant_orchestrator/src, services/assistant_orchestrator/tests, services/semantic_router/src, and services/semantic_router/tests.
      It must answer the four Task 7 audit questions for these two services only: coverage gaps, stale or dead tests, assertion quality, and boundary correctness.
      It must also append ledger Entry 40 to docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md.
      No production files or test files may be changed.
    </objective>

    <scope>
      Read exactly these in-scope source and test files, excluding __init__.py from coverage counts:

      assistant_orchestrator production files:
      - circuit_breaker.py
      - constants.py
      - context_manager.py
      - entrypoint.py
      - gpu_inference.py
      - pgov.py

      assistant_orchestrator test files:
      - test_circuit_breaker.py
      - test_context_manager.py
      - test_entrypoint.py
      - test_gpu_inference.py
      - test_pgov.py

      semantic_router production files:
      - constants.py
      - intents.py
      - router.py

      semantic_router test files:
      - test_router.py
    </scope>

    <work_items>
      <item id="WI-1">Inventory all 9 production files and all 6 test files in scope before drawing conclusions.</item>
      <item id="WI-2">Append coverage mapping findings for assistant_orchestrator and semantic_router to docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md.</item>
      <item id="WI-3">Append stale or dead test findings for both services.</item>
      <item id="WI-4">Append assertion quality findings for both services.</item>
      <item id="WI-5">Append boundary correctness findings for both services.</item>
      <item id="WI-6">Append ledger Entry 40 to docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md.</item>
      <item id="WI-7">Enforce strict DOC_ONLY hygiene: stage and commit only the two allowed docs files.</item>
      <item id="WI-8">Use Tier 3 fail-safe if the full scope cannot be completed without quality degradation.</item>
    </work_items>
  </milestone>

  <deliverable>
    <primary_artifact>
      Modify docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md. Preserve all accepted EA-1 content and append EA-2 findings only.
    </primary_artifact>

    <exact_structure>
      docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md must continue to contain exactly these 6 top-level sections in this exact order:
      1. ## Coverage Map
      2. ## Stale Test Inventory
      3. ## Assertion Quality Findings
      4. ## Boundary Violations
      5. ## Prioritized Gap Report
      6. ## Pre-existing Skip Analysis

      Under sections 1-4, append new clearly labeled subsections for:
      - ### assistant_orchestrator
      - ### semantic_router

      Content boundaries:
      - Append assistant_orchestrator and semantic_router findings to sections 1-4 only.
      - Preserve all accepted EA-1 findings as-is. Do NOT rewrite or re-litigate EA-1 conclusions.
      - Sections 5 and 6 must remain exactly: Deferred to EA-5 synthesis.
      - You MAY make a minimal title or preamble adjustment if needed so the document no longer reads as policy_agent-only.
      - Do NOT add any new top-level sections.
    </exact_structure>

    <coverage_map_contract>
      Under ## Coverage Map, every in-scope production file must be mapped to its test file(s) with a qualitative coverage assessment and brief rationale.
      Use a format compatible with the accepted EA-1 document. Do not reformat the entire section merely to normalize taxonomy.
      The assistant_orchestrator subsection must represent all 6 production files.
      The semantic_router subsection must represent all 3 production files.
    </coverage_map_contract>

    <stale_inventory_contract>
      Under ## Stale Test Inventory, record any stale imports, dead code references, renamed module paths, superseded architectural assumptions, or obsolete terminology that no longer matches current production reality.
      If a service has no stale or dead findings, state that explicitly.
    </stale_inventory_contract>

    <assertion_quality_contract>
      Under ## Assertion Quality Findings, include a short per-service summary paragraph plus a flat list of specific weak-assertion findings with test file and rationale.
      If a service has no material assertion-quality findings, state that explicitly.
    </assertion_quality_contract>

    <boundary_contract>
      Under ## Boundary Violations, evaluate whether any in-scope tests make real socket connections, perform real filesystem writes beyond isolated scaffolding, depend on live services or hardware, or should really be integration tests rather than service-level unit tests.
      If a service has no material boundary violations, state that explicitly.
    </boundary_contract>

    <ledger_contract>
      Append Entry 40 to docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md using the existing ledger format.

      Required content:
      - Title: Entry 40 - Task 7/EA-2: Assistant Orchestrator + Semantic Router Audit (COMPLETE)
      - Date: 2026-04-18 or actual execution date
      - Branch: feature/p5-task7-ea2-ao-sr-audit
      - Predecessor: Entry 39 - Task 7/EA-1: Policy Agent Test Suite Audit
      - Type: AUDIT / DOCS-ONLY
      - Disposition: COMPLETE
      - Summary: EA-2 completed; assistant_orchestrator and semantic_router findings appended to docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md; sections 5-6 remain deferred to EA-5
      - Files: docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md and docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md only
    </ledger_contract>
  </deliverable>

  <negative_constraints>
    <item>DO NOT add numbered prefixes to any required ## top-level section headers.</item>
    <item>DO NOT add top-level sections beyond the 6 required sections.</item>
    <item>DO NOT rename any of the 6 required top-level sections.</item>
    <item>DO NOT populate ## Prioritized Gap Report with findings. Leave it exactly: Deferred to EA-5 synthesis.</item>
    <item>DO NOT populate ## Pre-existing Skip Analysis with findings. Leave it exactly: Deferred to EA-5 synthesis.</item>
    <item>DO NOT rewrite, restructure, or re-litigate accepted EA-1 findings, except for a minimal title or preamble adjustment if needed.</item>
    <item>DO NOT modify any file under services/assistant_orchestrator/src/.</item>
    <item>DO NOT modify any file under services/assistant_orchestrator/tests/.</item>
    <item>DO NOT modify any file under services/semantic_router/src/.</item>
    <item>DO NOT modify any file under services/semantic_router/tests/.</item>
    <item>DO NOT modify pyproject.toml.</item>
    <item>DO NOT modify docs/TEST_GOVERNANCE.md.</item>
    <item>DO NOT modify docs/IMPLEMENTATION_PLAN.md for this audit slice.</item>
    <item>DO NOT create or modify conftest.py.</item>
    <item>DO NOT add, remove, rename, or fix tests.</item>
    <item>DO NOT run coverage tooling or install dependencies.</item>
    <item>DO NOT touch unrelated pre-existing untracked files in the worktree.</item>
  </negative_constraints>

  <quality_gate>
    <gate id="COMPILE" order="1">
      <command>N/A - DOCS-ONLY audit milestone</command>
      <criteria>No Python files may be created or modified in this milestone.</criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="TEST" order="2">
      <command>N/A - DOCS-ONLY audit milestone</command>
      <criteria>
        Do not run pytest as a standard gate for this slice.
        Use file inspection as the primary evidence source.
        If you run a targeted read-only command to confirm a suspected stale reference, report it explicitly in your session close-out.
      </criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="ORACLE_1" order="3">
      <command>Manual audit completion against all 9 production files and all 6 test files in scope</command>
      <criteria>
        All 6 assistant_orchestrator production files, all 5 assistant_orchestrator test files,
        all 3 semantic_router production files, and the semantic_router test file are evaluated.
      </criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="ORACLE_2" order="4">
      <command>Review docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md structure</command>
      <criteria>
        The document still contains the same 6 required top-level sections in the same order.
        assistant_orchestrator and semantic_router findings are appended under sections 1-4 only.
        Sections 5 and 6 remain exactly: Deferred to EA-5 synthesis.
      </criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="ORACLE_3" order="5">
      <command>git diff --staged --name-only 488b198</command>
      <criteria>
        Output contains ONLY:
        - docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md
        - docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md
      </criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="ORACLE_4" order="6">
      <command>Tier 3 fail-safe check</command>
      <criteria>
        If the full scope was not completable without quality degradation, STOP,
        leave a clearly labeled partial report, record partial status in Entry 40,
        and recommend a re-scope instead of rushing.
      </criteria>
    </gate>
  </quality_gate>

  <verification>
    <instruction>
      The Lead Architect will verify this milestone using terminal commands only.
      Your final EA response must report results that these commands can confirm.
    </instruction>

    <commands>
      <command>git branch --show-current</command>
      <expected>feature/p5-task7-ea2-ao-sr-audit</expected>

      <command>git log --oneline -1</command>
      <expected>Single EA-2 audit commit on the feature branch</expected>

      <command>git diff 488b198 --name-only</command>
      <expected>
        docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md
        docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md
      </expected>

      <command>Select-String -Path docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md -Pattern "^## ","^### assistant_orchestrator","^### semantic_router","Deferred to EA-5 synthesis"</command>
      <expected>
        Shows the 6 required top-level sections, the new assistant_orchestrator and semantic_router subsections,
        and the unchanged deferred placeholders
      </expected>

      <command>Select-String -Path docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md -Pattern "Entry 40" | Select-Object -First 1</command>
      <expected>Ledger contains Entry 40 for Task 7 / EA-2</expected>
    </commands>
  </verification>

  <commit_template>
    <message>
Task 7 EA-2: Audit assistant_orchestrator and semantic_router test quality

- Appended assistant_orchestrator findings to docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md
- Appended semantic_router findings to docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md
- Preserved deferred sections for Prioritized Gap Report and Pre-existing Skip Analysis
- Recorded ledger Entry 40 in Post-Operational Maturation Ledger

DOC_ONLY gate: diff against 488b198 contains only docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md
and docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md
    </message>
  </commit_template>

  <required_attachments>
    <file reason="Canonical audit rubric">docs/TEST_GOVERNANCE.md</file>
    <file reason="Root pytest configuration and marker policy source">pyproject.toml</file>
    <file reason="Merged Task 7 artifact to append to">docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md</file>
    <file reason="Ledger format and latest audit entry reference">docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md</file>
    <file reason="This execution prompt">docs/P5_TASK7_EA2_AO_SR_AUDIT.xml</file>
  </required_attachments>

  <context_notes>
    <note id="CN-1">
      docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md is now the merged EA-1 artifact from main. It currently reads as policy_agent-focused.
      A minimal document title or preamble adjustment is permitted if needed, but do not alter the six required ## section headers.
    </note>

    <note id="CN-2">
      Existing accepted EA-1 content includes numbered ### subsections. Preserve that content as-is.
      The prohibition on numbered prefixes applies to the required ## top-level section headers and any new ## headers.
      For new append content, prefer plain service headings: ### assistant_orchestrator and ### semantic_router.
    </note>

    <note id="CN-3">
      assistant_orchestrator was migrated from NPU naming to GPU naming in Task 5.
      Any remaining NPU terminology in tests may be a stale-naming finding, but distinguish cosmetic stale terminology from functional dead imports or dead module paths.
    </note>

    <note id="CN-4">
      docs/TEST_GOVERNANCE.md is the governing standard for this audit.
      Use its scope definitions, marker policy, boundary rules, and coverage expectations as the rubric.
    </note>

    <note id="CN-5">
      pyproject.toml defines addopts = "--strict-markers -v --import-mode=importlib -m 'not slow'" and registered markers asyncio and slow.
      No slow-marker usage is expected in services/assistant_orchestrator/tests or services/semantic_router/tests.
    </note>

    <note id="CN-6">
      Coverage assessment is qualitative. Do not install or run coverage tooling.
      Map code to tests by inspection and assess adequacy against happy-path plus error or edge-path expectations.
    </note>

    <note id="CN-7">
      The two pre-existing skipped tests remain a document-level synthesis concern for EA-5.
      Do not analyze or disposition them in EA-2.
    </note>
  </context_notes>

</execution_prompt>
