<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<execution_prompt version="1.0" task="P5-Task-7" milestone="EA-2-CORRECTION">

  <comprehension_gate>
    <instruction>
      MANDATORY FIRST ACTION: Before any branch creation, file edits, or commands, read this entire prompt and all required attachments in full.
      Then present a structured comprehension summary to the Lead Architect covering:
        (a) corrective objective in your own words
        (b) work items with 1 sentence each
        (c) files to READ and files to WRITE
        (d) exact structural and taxonomy defects being corrected
        (e) ORACLE strategy for this DOCS-ONLY corrective milestone
        (f) risks or ambiguities
        (g) EXACT deliverable structure, recited VERBATIM from this prompt:
            - branch to create: feature/p5-task7-ea2-ao-sr-audit-correction from main at 6ab1ece
            - files to WRITE: docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md and docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md only
            - docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md must retain exactly these 6 top-level sections in this order:
              1. ## Coverage Map
              2. ## Stale Test Inventory
              3. ## Assertion Quality Findings
              4. ## Boundary Violations
              5. ## Prioritized Gap Report
              6. ## Pre-existing Skip Analysis
            - under sections 1-4, preserve ### policy_agent and append ### assistant_orchestrator and ### semantic_router only
            - the two misclassified findings must be reclassified out of ## Boundary Violations:
              * Exact PGOV leakage threshold (0.85) untested
              * semantic_router dual-gate threshold and margin exact boundaries untested
            - under Coverage Map, use the exact labels:
              * #### Exact PGOV Leakage Threshold (0.85) Untested
              * #### Dual-Gate Threshold and Margin Boundaries Untested
            - under ## Boundary Violations, preserve the AO cross-service import finding if re-review confirms it
            - if no true semantic_router boundary-correctness violations remain after re-review, the semantic_router boundary subsection must say exactly:
              No material boundary violations identified for semantic_router.
            - append Entry 41 for this milestone
      Then STOP and WAIT for explicit Lead Architect approval.
      Do NOT create the branch, write files, or run commands until the Lead Architect confirms that your recitation is correct.
    </instruction>
  </comprehension_gate>

  <milestone>
    <id>P5-TASK7-EA2-CORRECTION</id>
    <title>Task 7 / EA-2 Correction: Assistant Orchestrator + Semantic Router Audit Re-execution on Corrected Main</title>
    <type>DOCS-ONLY CORRECTIVE AUDIT</type>
    <recommended_model>claude-opus-4.6</recommended_model>
    <model_rationale>Constraint-heavy DOCS-ONLY correction against a shared merged artifact with strict structure, taxonomy, and ledger requirements.</model_rationale>
    <branch>feature/p5-task7-ea2-ao-sr-audit-correction</branch>
    <parent_branch>main</parent_branch>
    <parent_head>6ab1ece</parent_head>
    <branch_command>git checkout -b feature/p5-task7-ea2-ao-sr-audit-correction 6ab1ece</branch_command>
    <predecessor>Main HEAD 6ab1ece includes the merged EA-1 correction plus later Vikunja infra commits. Those later commits do not touch docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md or docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md. The original EA-2 branch remains unmerged, is based on stale main state 488b198, and contains unrelated docs commits beyond the audit work.</predecessor>
    <harness_declaration>NO_FULL_HARNESS</harness_declaration>

    <required_attachments>
      <file>.github/copilot-instructions.md</file>
      <file>docs/TEST_GOVERNANCE.md</file>
      <file>docs/P5_TASK7_EA2_AO_SR_AUDIT.xml</file>
      <file>docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md</file>
      <file>docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md</file>
      <file>docs/P5_TASK7_EA1_POLICY_AGENT_AUDIT_CORRECTION.xml</file>
    </required_attachments>

    <objective>
      Re-execute EA-2 against corrected main state and append assistant_orchestrator plus semantic_router findings to the canonical Task 7 artifact without reintroducing the structural and taxonomy errors found during oversight review.
      This is not a production-code milestone and not a continuation of the old EA-2 branch.
      You must preserve accepted policy_agent content from main, port the accepted EA-2 substantive findings into the current artifact, correct the boundary taxonomy, normalize the top-of-file metadata so the artifact no longer reads as policy_agent-only, and append ledger Entry 41.
      No production files or test files may be changed.
    </objective>

    <correction_basis>
      <item>The current main artifact is structurally corrected for EA-1 and contains only policy_agent findings.</item>
      <item>The original EA-2 branch is not safe to merge directly because it is based on stale main state and includes unrelated docs commits (`docs/BOOT_SEQUENCE_GOVERNANCE.md` and a later revision) beyond the audit work.</item>
      <item>Independent oversight found two misclassified EA-2 boundary items: AO exact PGOV threshold 0.85 untested, and semantic_router exact dual-gate boundaries untested. These are coverage gaps, not boundary-correctness violations.</item>
      <item>The AO cross-service import finding is potentially a real boundary violation and must be re-reviewed rather than discarded.</item>
    </correction_basis>

    <scope>
      Re-read exactly these in-scope source and test files, excluding __init__.py from coverage counts:

      assistant_orchestrator production files:
      - services/assistant_orchestrator/src/circuit_breaker.py
      - services/assistant_orchestrator/src/constants.py
      - services/assistant_orchestrator/src/context_manager.py
      - services/assistant_orchestrator/src/entrypoint.py
      - services/assistant_orchestrator/src/gpu_inference.py
      - services/assistant_orchestrator/src/pgov.py

      assistant_orchestrator test files:
      - services/assistant_orchestrator/tests/test_circuit_breaker.py
      - services/assistant_orchestrator/tests/test_context_manager.py
      - services/assistant_orchestrator/tests/test_entrypoint.py
      - services/assistant_orchestrator/tests/test_gpu_inference.py
      - services/assistant_orchestrator/tests/test_pgov.py

      semantic_router production files:
      - services/semantic_router/src/constants.py
      - services/semantic_router/src/intents.py
      - services/semantic_router/src/router.py

      semantic_router test files:
      - services/semantic_router/tests/test_router.py

      In addition to the source/test re-read, use the old EA-2 branch as reference only:
      - feature/p5-task7-ea2-ao-sr-audit:docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md
      - feature/p5-task7-ea2-ao-sr-audit:docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md

      Do not continue work on the old branch. Do not carry over unrelated docs commits.
    </scope>

    <work_items>
      <item id="WI-1">Re-read all 9 production files and all 6 test files in scope before changing the artifact.</item>
      <item id="WI-2">Update docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md header and metadata so the document no longer reads as policy_agent-only.</item>
      <item id="WI-3">Append assistant_orchestrator and semantic_router findings under sections 1-4 only, preserving the corrected ### policy_agent pattern already on main.</item>
      <item id="WI-4">Preserve accepted EA-2 coverage, stale, and assertion findings from the old branch unless the source re-read requires a factual correction.</item>
      <item id="WI-5">Reclassify the two misfiled numeric-boundary findings from Section 4 into Coverage Map using the exact required labels.</item>
      <item id="WI-6">Rewrite the EA-2 boundary subsection so it contains only true boundary-correctness findings under the Task 7 contract.</item>
      <item id="WI-7">Remove obsolete numbered or section-based internal cross-references from EA-2 content and ledger summary text.</item>
      <item id="WI-8">Append Entry 41 to docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md using current main numbering.</item>
      <item id="WI-9">Enforce strict DOC_ONLY hygiene: stage and commit only the two allowed docs files.</item>
      <item id="WI-10">Use Tier 3 fail-safe if the correction cannot be completed without quality degradation.</item>
    </work_items>
  </milestone>

  <deliverable>
    <primary_artifact>
      Modify docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md on main-derived state. Preserve accepted policy_agent content from main exactly as-is unless a minimal preamble or header normalization is required.
    </primary_artifact>

    <header_contract>
      Replace the current single-EA header block with a multi-EA header that no longer reads as policy_agent-only.

      Required top block:
      - Title exactly: # Test Audit Findings
      - Keep:
        **Audit Type:** DOCS-ONLY qualitative audit — no production or test file modifications
        **Governance Reference:** `docs/TEST_GOVERNANCE.md`
      - Add an EA index table with rows for:
        * EA-1: services/policy_agent, branch feature/p5-task7-ea1-policy-agent-audit, commit baseline 88b330d, ledger Entry 39
        * EA-2: services/assistant_orchestrator and services/semantic_router, branch feature/p5-task7-ea2-ao-sr-audit-correction, commit baseline 6ab1ece, ledger Entry 41
    </header_contract>

    <exact_structure>
      docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md must continue to contain exactly these 6 top-level sections in this exact order:
      1. ## Coverage Map
      2. ## Stale Test Inventory
      3. ## Assertion Quality Findings
      4. ## Boundary Violations
      5. ## Prioritized Gap Report
      6. ## Pre-existing Skip Analysis

      Under sections 1-4 only, the allowed service headings are:
      - ### policy_agent
      - ### assistant_orchestrator
      - ### semantic_router

      Preserve the existing ### policy_agent content from main.
      Append new assistant_orchestrator and semantic_router content after the policy_agent subsection within each relevant section.
      Sections 5 and 6 must remain exactly:
      - Deferred to EA-5 synthesis.
    </exact_structure>

    <coverage_contract>
      Under ## Coverage Map:
      - preserve the corrected policy_agent content already on main
      - append assistant_orchestrator findings under ### assistant_orchestrator
      - append semantic_router findings under ### semantic_router
      - remove or update any EA-2 coverage text that points readers to the old Section 4 placement
      - use these exact descriptive labels for the reclassified findings:
        * #### Exact PGOV Leakage Threshold (0.85) Untested
        * #### Dual-Gate Threshold and Margin Boundaries Untested
      - if the reclassification means a module should no longer be described as COMPREHENSIVE, update the table and rationale accordingly
    </coverage_contract>

    <stale_contract>
      Under ## Stale Test Inventory:
      - append assistant_orchestrator stale findings under ### assistant_orchestrator
      - append semantic_router stale findings under ### semantic_router
      - if semantic_router has no stale findings, state that explicitly
    </stale_contract>

    <assertion_contract>
      Under ## Assertion Quality Findings:
      - append assistant_orchestrator findings under ### assistant_orchestrator
      - append semantic_router findings under ### semantic_router
      - preserve the accepted assertion findings from the old EA-2 branch unless the re-read requires a factual correction
      - remove obsolete numbered cross-references or section references from the imported EA-2 text
    </assertion_contract>

    <boundary_contract>
      Under ## Boundary Violations:
      - preserve ### policy_agent exactly as it exists on main
      - append ### assistant_orchestrator
      - append ### semantic_router

      Boundary-correctness means only:
      - real socket connections
      - real filesystem writes beyond isolated scaffolding
      - dependence on live services or hardware
      - tests that should really be integration tests rather than service-level unit tests

      The following do NOT belong in this section:
      - exact numeric threshold coverage gaps
      - untested value boundaries
      - missing edge-case assertions that are really coverage findings

      assistant_orchestrator:
      - preserve the old-branch finding under the exact label #### Cross-Service Import in Test Suite only if the re-read confirms it still qualifies as a material boundary issue
      - do not reinsert the exact PGOV threshold coverage gap here

      semantic_router:
      - do not place the dual-gate threshold/margin gap here
      - if no true semantic_router boundary violations exist, write exactly:
        No material boundary violations identified for semantic_router.
    </boundary_contract>

    <ledger_contract>
      Append Entry 41 to docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md using the existing ledger format.

      Required content:
      - Title: Entry 41 - Task 7/EA-2: Assistant Orchestrator + Semantic Router Audit (COMPLETE)
      - Date: 2026-04-18 or actual execution date
      - Branch: feature/p5-task7-ea2-ao-sr-audit-correction
      - Predecessor: Entry 40 - Task 7/EA-1 Correction: Policy Agent Audit Structural and Taxonomy Fix
      - Type: AUDIT / DOCS-ONLY
      - Disposition: COMPLETE
      - Summary: EA-2 completed against corrected main; assistant_orchestrator and semantic_router findings appended to docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md; exact-threshold coverage gaps recorded under Coverage Map; boundary section limited to true boundary-correctness findings; sections 5-6 remain deferred to EA-5
      - Files: docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md and docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md only

      In Entry 41 summary and key findings:
      - do not use numbered section references such as §5.3, §5.4, or §5.5
      - do not describe the two reclassified items as boundary tests
    </ledger_contract>
  </deliverable>

  <negative_constraints>
    <item>DO NOT continue work on feature/p5-task7-ea2-ao-sr-audit.</item>
    <item>DO NOT modify docs/BOOT_SEQUENCE_GOVERNANCE.md.</item>
    <item>DO NOT carry over unrelated docs commits from the old EA-2 branch.</item>
    <item>DO NOT modify any file under services/assistant_orchestrator/src/.</item>
    <item>DO NOT modify any file under services/assistant_orchestrator/tests/.</item>
    <item>DO NOT modify any file under services/semantic_router/src/.</item>
    <item>DO NOT modify any file under services/semantic_router/tests/.</item>
    <item>DO NOT modify docs/TEST_GOVERNANCE.md.</item>
    <item>DO NOT modify docs/IMPLEMENTATION_PLAN.md.</item>
    <item>DO NOT add top-level sections beyond the 6 required sections.</item>
    <item>DO NOT rename any of the 6 required top-level sections.</item>
    <item>DO NOT rewrite or re-litigate accepted policy_agent findings from main.</item>
    <item>DO NOT populate ## Prioritized Gap Report with findings. Leave it exactly: Deferred to EA-5 synthesis.</item>
    <item>DO NOT populate ## Pre-existing Skip Analysis with findings. Leave it exactly: Deferred to EA-5 synthesis.</item>
    <item>DO NOT leave the AO exact PGOV threshold or semantic_router dual-gate exact-boundary findings under ## Boundary Violations.</item>
    <item>DO NOT use git add .</item>
    <item>DO NOT run coverage tooling or install dependencies.</item>
    <item>DO NOT touch unrelated pre-existing untracked files in the worktree.</item>
  </negative_constraints>

  <quality_gate>
    <gate id="COMPILE" order="1">
      <command>N/A - DOCS-ONLY corrective milestone</command>
      <criteria>No Python files may be created or modified in this milestone.</criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="TEST" order="2">
      <command>N/A - DOCS-ONLY corrective milestone</command>
      <criteria>
        Do not run pytest as a standard gate for this slice.
        Use file inspection as the primary evidence source.
        If you run a targeted read-only command to confirm a reference or boundary claim, report it explicitly in your session close-out.
      </criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="ORACLE_1" order="3">
      <command>Manual audit completion against all 9 production files and all 6 test files in scope</command>
      <criteria>
        All 6 assistant_orchestrator production files, all 5 assistant_orchestrator test files,
        all 3 semantic_router production files, and the semantic_router test file are re-evaluated.
        The two misclassified numeric-boundary findings are confirmed as real coverage issues before reclassification.
      </criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="ORACLE_2" order="4">
      <command>Review docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md structure and header</command>
      <criteria>
        The top title is exactly # Test Audit Findings.
        The document still contains the same 6 required top-level sections in the same order.
        Sections 1-4 contain only ### policy_agent, ### assistant_orchestrator, and ### semantic_router service headings.
        Sections 5 and 6 remain exactly: Deferred to EA-5 synthesis.
      </criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="ORACLE_3" order="5">
      <command>Review coverage and boundary subsection content</command>
      <criteria>
        The exact labels #### Exact PGOV Leakage Threshold (0.85) Untested and #### Dual-Gate Threshold and Margin Boundaries Untested appear under ## Coverage Map.
        Those findings do not remain under ## Boundary Violations.
        assistant_orchestrator boundary content contains only true boundary-correctness findings.
        If semantic_router has no true boundary violations, its subsection contains the exact sentence: No material boundary violations identified for semantic_router.
      </criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="ORACLE_4" order="6">
      <command>Review docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md metadata</command>
      <criteria>
        Entry 41 exists and matches the required title, date, predecessor, type, and disposition.
        Entry 41 does not use numbered section references and does not describe the reclassified items as boundary tests.
      </criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="ORACLE_5" order="7">
      <command>git diff --staged --name-only 6ab1ece</command>
      <criteria>
        Output contains ONLY:
        - docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md
        - docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md
      </criteria>
    </gate>

    <gate id="ORACLE_6" order="8">
      <command>Tier 3 fail-safe check</command>
      <criteria>
        If the correction cannot be completed without degraded quality, STOP,
        leave a clearly labeled partial correction, record partial status in Entry 41,
        and recommend a re-scope instead of forcing a weak close-out.
      </criteria>
    </gate>
  </quality_gate>

  <verification>
    <instruction>
      The Lead Architect will verify this corrective milestone using terminal commands only.
      Your final EA response must report results that these commands can confirm.
    </instruction>

    <commands>
      <command>git branch --show-current</command>
      <expected>feature/p5-task7-ea2-ao-sr-audit-correction</expected>

      <command>git log --oneline -1</command>
      <expected>Single EA-2 correction commit on the feature branch</expected>

      <command>git diff 6ab1ece --name-only</command>
      <expected>
        docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md
        docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md
      </expected>

      <command>Select-String -Path docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md -Pattern "^# Test Audit Findings$","^## ","^### policy_agent$","^### assistant_orchestrator$","^### semantic_router$","^#### Exact PGOV Leakage Threshold \\(0\\.85\\) Untested$","^#### Dual-Gate Threshold and Margin Boundaries Untested$","^#### Cross-Service Import in Test Suite$","^No material boundary violations identified for semantic_router\\.$","Deferred to EA-5 synthesis"</command>
      <expected>
        Shows the normalized multi-EA header, the 6 required top-level sections, the allowed service headings,
        the two reclassified coverage findings, the AO cross-service boundary finding if retained, the semantic_router no-violation sentence, and the unchanged deferred placeholders.
      </expected>

      <command>Select-String -Path docs/POST_OPERATIONAL_MATURATION_LEDGER.md -Pattern "Entry 41","Type: AUDIT / DOCS-ONLY","Disposition: COMPLETE" | Select-Object -First 6</command>
      <expected>Ledger contains contract-compliant Entry 41 for EA-2 on corrected main.</expected>
    </commands>
  </verification>

  <commit_template>
    <message>
Task 7 EA-2 correction: append AO and semantic router audit on corrected main

- Appended assistant_orchestrator and semantic_router findings to docs/TEST_AUDIT_FINDINGS.md
- Reclassified numeric boundary gaps into Coverage Map and limited Boundary Violations to true boundary issues
- Added Entry 41 in Post-Operational Maturation Ledger
    </message>
  </commit_template>

</execution_prompt>
